（グィー）
やめて…
Stop.
やめてよ… やめて
帰りたい
I want to go home.
I want to go home!
帰りたい
Where do those scars lie within your chest?
sono kizu wa mune no doko ni arimasu ka?
Can you hear my voice somewhere inside your heart?
kono koe wa kokoro no dokoka de kikoeteimasu ka?
When your scars and mine join together...
sono kizu to kono kizu wo kasaneta nara
When my voice and yours resound together...
kono koe to sono koe wo hibikaseta nara
Our intensity, hot tears, and bashful smiles...
hageshisa atsui namida hazukashisou na hohoemi
I used to think nothing of them, but now,
anna ni mo nanimo nai tte omoeteta watashi kara
So many unstoppable feelings are overflowing!
afuredasu yo konna ni mo tomedo nai kanjou ga ima
You're the one who finds yourself.
kimi ga kimi wo mitsukedasu
You're the one who saves yourself.
kimi ga kimi wo sukuidasu
So much is wrong and everyone breaks into a run.
machigai darake de daremo ga hashiridasu
You're the one who lives your own life,
kimi ga kimi wo ikite yuku
Trembling, hesitating all the while
furue nagara, tomadoi nagara
In a world where you're never truly alone.
hitori kiri janai sekai
But you're the only one of you there is!
dakedo kimi wa tatta ichi nin kimi shika inai
That girl, Hatori Chise, is officially dead in Japan.
（アドルフ）あの子… ハトリ チセ
日本で死んだことになってました
So I chose a location here and plugged her in.
なんで こっちで
適当な地区に差し込みましたよ
Thanks, Adolf.
（レンフレッド）悪いな アドルフ
No, I'm glad you told me.
（アドルフ）
いえ 教えてくれて 助かりました
Sleigh Beggies are valuable.
夜の愛し仔(スレイ･ベガ)は貴重ですから
The ones with potential and
ambition are treasures, aren't they?
資質や意欲のある子は財産だろ
Of course.
（アドルフ）それは もちろ…
帰って！
Go home!
Don't you like it?
（レンフレッド）好きだろ
I don't want to drink with you!
（アドルフ）
あんたと飲むのが嫌なんです！
It's a Christmas gift from Alice.
（レンフレッド）
アリスからの
クリスマスプレゼントだ
ハア… １杯だけですよ
Just one shot, then.
You got a minute?
（トーリー）今 暇か〜？
Tory.
（アドルフ）トーリー
What's up with you?
（トーリー）
なんだい ２人して ひどい顔だぜ
You both look terrible.
Couldn't you come in here more quietly?
（レンフレッド）
もっと静かに入ってこい
Hey, you're drinking.
おっ！ 酒じゃないか〜
Don't mind if I do.
ちょっと僕も ご相伴にあずかろう
I never said you could touch that.
勝手に触るな
ん？ その腕 まだ治してないの？
You still haven't fixed that arm of yours?
カルタフィルス… でしたっけ
Cartaphilus, was it?
Have you had contact with him since?
あれから 接触は？
（レンフレッド）いや
Nope.
Lucky you.
（トーリー）
いいなあ〜 僕にも紹介してよ
Hook me up.
Here we go again.
（アドルフ）あんたは また…
（トーリー）
世紀をまたいだ
漂流の魔術師だろ？
A sorcerer that's been wandering for centuries, huh?
Eternal life is a timeless theme.
不老不死は永遠のテーマさ
What a pathetic dream.
くだらん夢だ
You're so stuck-up.
潔癖だなあ
Brilliant, but you'll make enemies being like that.
優秀だけど
そういうとこ 敵 作るぞ
（レンフレッド）
味方なんぞ 数人いれば 十分だろう
I don't need more than a few people on my side.
Anyway, anyway...
Tory, that's too much!
（アドルフ）
あっ トーリー！ それ以上は！
（トーリー）
何だよ〜 少しぐらい いいだろ
Come on, just a little!
No!
（アドルフ）ダメですって
I'm not brilliant.
（レンフレッド）
俺は優秀なんかじゃない…
If I were brilliant, I wouldn't
have let myself be threatened by him.
優秀だったら
そもそも
あんなヤツに脅されなんか…
What the heck?!
えっ 何 これ？ 超面白い！
This is hilarious!
That's going to go on for
another four hours, at least. Good luck.
それ あと４時間は続きますから
よろしく
何 それ？ 超面倒
What the heck?
What a huge pain.
Drink with me!
（レンフレッド）お前も飲め！
（トーリー）アドルフ 助けて！
（アドルフ）やめてください
Help me!
（アドルフ）
引っ張らないでください！
Don't tug on me!
Huh?
（セルキー）あれ？ なんです？
What is this, it's not just Adolf?
アドルフだけじゃない
じゃないですか
メリトゥーリ！
Merituuli.
妖精？
A fairy?
師匠だった人の使い魔です
He's my former master's familiar.
London...
（チセ）
ロンドン？
Weird, I don't feel groggy.
何だろう… 体が重たくない
I'm not coughing, either.
咳(せき)も出ない
I'm neither warm nor cold.
寒くも暖かくもない
Hey, are you all right?
（チセ）あの… 大丈夫？
（カルタフィルス）痛い！
Ow!
Sorry, thanks.
ごめんね ありがとう
Cartaphilus.
カルタフィルス…
You know my name?
（カルタフィルス）
君… 僕の名前 知ってるの？
Huh?
（カルタフィルス）
あれ… 僕の名前
カルタフィルスっていうんだっけ？
My name...
Was my name Cartaphilus?
Miss, I can see through you.
お姉さん 透けてるけど…
もしかして 幽霊？
Are you a ghost?
（カルタフィルス）ダメだよ
You need to go where you belong.
ちゃんと行くべき所に行かなきゃ
Right?
Otherwise, it's just not right, is it?
（カルタフィルス）
だって
そうじゃなきゃ おかしいよね？
こんな…
I'm...
あっ… 痛い！
Ow!
痛い… ううっ！
I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい ごめんなさい
Sorry! Sorry! I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい ごめんなさい…
だけど！
But...
But, he...
だって 彼が…
（チセ）カルタ…
Carta—
（カルタフィルス）
俺は そんな呪われた
名前なんかじゃない！
I don't have such a cursed name!
カルタフィルス…
Cartaphilus...
ハア… ハア…
I'm...
俺は…
I'm Joseph.
僕は… ヨセフだ
助けて…
Help me.
Forgive me, Cartaphilus.
（カルタフィルス）
僕を許して カルタフィルス
What do we need to do to be saved?
どうしたら 僕たちは救われるの？
ハア… ハア…
That wasn't a dream.
（チセ）
夢… じゃない
Who'd you go to see?
（ルツ）誰の所に行ってたんだ？
It's him...
（チセ）あいつ… カルタフィルス
Cartaphilus...
助けて…
Help me...
I can't get his voice out of my ears.
（チセ）
耳から離れない
How many days has it been now?
（チセ）今日で何日目？
You've only been sleeping for two days.
（ルツ）２日 寝ていただけだ
So, why is Lindel-san's Selkie here?
なんで リンデルさんのセルキーが
ここに？
んにゃ？
やっと起きたんですか？
You're finally awake.
ふあ〜
Hey, you're awake.
（アリス）
おっ！
目ぇ覚めたのか？
Alice.
アリス！ どうして…
Why...
I'll go let everyone know.
（セルキー）
自分は 皆様に
お伝えしてきますよ
We've got a nasty situation... A pretty bad one, actually.
めんどくせえっていうか
ちょっとヤベえことが
起きてる
Huh?
Can I just pick out any outfit for you?
服 適当でいいか？
Th-Thanks.
（チセ）あっ… ありがとう
By the way, Alice, how old are you?
ところで アリスって 何歳？
Eighteen this year.
（アリス）今年で18
Oh, that's fine, then.
なら いいんだ
Morning, Chise.
（エリアス）おはよう チセ
Good morning.
おはよう… ございます
How do you feel?
（エリアス）気分は？
Well, thank you.
おかげさまで
How about you?
エリアスは？
Well, thank you.
（エリアス）おかげさまで
I've never been able to get a
good look at a living Sleigh Beggy!
生きてるスレイ･ベガを
しっかり観察できるなんて
初めてだ！
I'm so glad I got to meet you.
君に会えて とってもうれしいよ
生きていてくれて ありがとう！
Thank you for being alive!
あう… あの？
U-Um...
アリス
Alice.
I hate to admit that he's my
colleague, but sorry about my colleague.
（アドルフ）
同輩… と言いたくないですが
同輩が失礼しました
Nice to meet you.
はじめまして
俺はアドルフ･ストラウド
I'm Adolf Stroud.
Nice to meet you.
はじめまして
Long time no see.
久しぶりだな
Sorry about my disrespectful behavior last time.
あのときは失礼をした
It's fine.
気にしないでください
ぼ… 僕はトーリー･イニス
I'm Tory Innis.
トーリーって呼んでくれ
You can call me Tory.
We're from the college.
（アドルフ）俺たちは学院(カレッジ)の者です
College?
（チセ）カレッジ？
（アドルフ）聞いてないですか？
You haven't heard?
（エリアス）世間話は いらないよ
You can cut the small talk.
さっさと本題に入ってくれないか
Can you get to business?
As we've already explained to him,
（アドルフ）
彼には もう言いましたが
dragon hatchlings were
poached from the land of dragons.
ドラゴンの国にいたドラゴンの雛(ひな)が
密猟に遭いました
Two were taken.
（アドルフ）さらわれたのは ２頭
The poacher left this behind.
密猟者が これを残していきました
What's that?
（エリアス）それは？
It's a transportation device I made.
（レンフレッド）
私が作った移動装置だ
今回のことは 恐らく
カルタフィルスの起こしたことだ
Cartaphilus is likely behind this incident.
He seems to have stolen the know-how
behind the device when he took my arm.
腕と一緒に
装置のノウハウも盗まれたらしい
私の不手際だ
This is my failure.
Master...
（エリアス）そのことは別にいいよ
Don't worry about that.
I understand well that you
didn't mean for this to happen.
君も不本意なのは よく理解できる
The question is why we need to join
you in finding Cartaphilus and the dragons.
問題は なぜ僕らが 一緒に
カルタフィルスとドラゴンを
捜さなきゃならないかってことだ
You have a friendship with the land of
dragons, and you're familiar with Cartaphilus.
あなたたちは
ドラゴンの国とも
親交があるし
カルタフィルスを
見知っている
Why is the college in the
business of looking for dragons, anyway?
（エリアス）
そもそも なんで カレッジが
ドラゴン捜しなんだ
Lindel-sama and the college have an agreement.
リンデル様とカレッジは
協定関係にあるのですよ
With Lindel-san?
（チセ）リンデルさんと？
Could you help us to bring the
dragons back to Lindel—to your friend?
（アドルフ）リンデルの…
あなたの友人のもとへ
ドラゴンたちを返す手伝いを
していただけませんか？
He's bound to that land. This is for his sake, too.
あそこへ縛られ続ける彼のためにも
Elias...
エリアス…
Nope.
（エリアス）ダメだよ
なんでですか？
Why not?
This isn't our business, and it's dangerous.
（エリアス）
僕らには関係ないし 危険だ
（チセ）でも！
But...
Have you forgotten how fragile your body is?
（エリアス）
君は
自分の体のもろさを忘れたのかい？
エリアスこそ
忘れてるんじゃないですか？
I think you've forgotten, too, Elias.
It was also extremely painful and agonizing,
すごく痛くて 苦しかったんですよ
あのとき…
that day.
That day?
（レンフレッド）
あのとき？
That day?
（トーリー）
あのとき？
"That" day?
（アドルフ）
あのとき？
エリアスの言うとおり
You're right, we're neither obliged nor responsible.
義務もなければ 責任もないです
But unlike us, the dragons left
the land of dragons against their will.
でも 雛たちは 私みたいに
望んで
ドラゴンの国を離れたわけじゃない
I don't want those kids I played with
一緒に遊んだあの子たちが
つらい思いをするのは…
嫌です
to suffer.
All right.
（エリアス）分かった　協力しよう
I'll cooperate.
Th-Thank you.
あ… ありがとうございます！
Have you changed a little?
（レンフレッド）
少し変わったか？
So, do we have any leads or ideas?
（エリアス）
それで？ 心当たりや手がかりは？
None on where Cartaphilus might be.
（アドルフ）
カルタフィルスのほうは
さっぱり…
We have Lindel maintaining contact
with the dragons, but things aren't very clear,
ドラゴンは リンデルに
交信を追ってもらってますが
possibly because they aren't fully conscious.
２頭とも意識が弱いせいか
不鮮明で…
I think Cartaphilus is in London.
（チセ）カルタフィルスは
多分 ロンドンにいると思います
（アドルフ）なぜ？
Why?
Well, it's a hunch.
（チセ）その… 勘なんですけど
ストラウドさん
Stroud-san, do dragons sell for a lot of money?
ドラゴンって… 高く売れますか？
Ye—
（アドルフ）そ…
（トーリー）売れるさ！
They sure do!
A lot of money.
ものすごく高くね
Then it's possible...
（チセ）
なら もしかすると…
Sorry, can someone lend me a phone?
すみません
誰か電話を貸してくれませんか？
Yes?
（セス）はい
ああ… あなたですか
Oh, it's you.
How are you?
調子は？
それはいい
That's great.
Yes.
ええ 今は パリにいますが
I'm in Paris right now.
Depending on price and terms, I may take on your work.
仕事ならば
金額と内容によっては
お受けいたしますよ
（係員Ａ）おい！
Come on!
Pull it tighter!
そっち もっと強く押さえろ！
Mr. Seth.
セスさん
Long time no see, Chise-san.
（セス）
お久しぶりですね チセさん
Oh, and Mr. Ainsworth?
と… エインズワース氏ですか？
I believe magic and sorcery
are not allowed at the auction.
魔法 魔術の類いは
競売場では
使用できないはずですが…
That's what I heard, so I'm
using neither magic nor sorcery.
（エリアス）
そう聞いたからね
魔法も魔術も使ってないよ
I just reassembled the whole thing.
丸ごと組み替えただけだ
It's neither me nor Simon.
（チセ）
サイモンさんでも 私でもなく
誰の顔なんだろう
Who's face is that?
I'll choose not to hear all your names.
（セス）皆さんのお名前は…
聞かないことにいたしましょう
Um, if it's possible, I'd like to contribute this.
（チセ）あの… これを
できれば 足しにしたいんですが
Oh, this is...
（セス）ああ これは…
Excellent.
いいですね
We'll make this the first item of the afternoon.
これを午後一番で競りにかけます
And then we'll move on to the main auction.
それから 本命の競りに
Is that all right?
よろしいですか？
Yes.
はい
The dragon auction begins at 6 PM.
（セス）
ドラゴンのオークションは
18時からです
Until then, feel free to do as you please.
それまでは ご自由に
You sure do sell whatever you want here.
（トーリー）
随分 自由な商品を
売ってるんだなあ
Chise-san, here.
チセさん これを
A checkbook?
（チセ）小切手帳？ カードも…
And a card.
Half of the value of your sale price is deposited there.
あなたの売値半額が
入金してあります
（チセ）は… 半額？
Half?!
You were both a product as well as an exhibitor,
商品であり 出品者でもあった
あなたの取り分ですよ
so that's your share.
Dragons are expensive.
ドラゴンは高額です
Please use that if the college's funding is inadequate.
カレッジ側の費用が足りなければ
お使いください
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
Money, huh?
（チセ）
お金か…
Come to think of it, this money really belongs to Elias.
そういえば これは
元は エリアスのお金なわけで
You have a different aura about you.
雰囲気が変わりましたね
You've grown taller, too.
背も伸びましたし
あのころとは別人だ
You're different from when we last met.
I've changed in some ways,
and stayed the same in others.
（チセ）
変わったところも
変わってないところもありますよ
The most important parts of a person seldom change.
（セス）
肝心要の部分は
そうそう変わりません
You're stubborn after all, for better or worse.
あなたは良くも悪くも
頑固ですしね
What's up?
（トーリー）何だ？ 何の話？
What were you talking about?
Hey, want to come to the college?
ねえ！ 君 カレッジへ来ないかい？
There's someone at home
who gets lonely when I'm not there.
家にいないと
寂しがるヒトがいるので
アハハハ 手ごわそうで何よりだ
Glad to see you're not easy.
If there's something you want to say, say it out loud.
（エリアス）
何か言いたいなら
口に出してくれないか？
You haven't told her about the college, have you?
お前 カレッジのことを
あの子に言ってないな
She's not going to the college.
あの子は カレッジには行かない
So there's no reason to tell her.
だから 言う必要もない
What did you do with the messenger?
使いをどうした？
壊したのか？
Did you destroy it?
It's unlike you to be so
fixated on a Sleigh Beggy, Renfred.
らしくないぞ レンフレッド
そんなに
スレイ･ベガに固執するなんて
It's not that I'm worried about a Sleigh Beggy.
俺は スレイ･ベガを
気にしているわけじゃない
I'm worried about the future of a human being.
人間である彼女の未来を
気にしてるんだ
She may be fine now,
今は よくても
依存先を お前に限定して
but how far is she going to grow if
she's forced to be dependent on you?
その先 どれだけ成長できる？
それを僕らが語るのかい？
Is that for us to discuss?
We find someone without direction,
burden them with a chest full of knowledge,
行く当てのない者に
知識の金庫を背負わせて
and force them onto a ship
that takes them into the future.
先へ運ぶ船へ 無理やり乗せる
We act as if we've shown them a path,
and make them believe it's the only path.
道を提示したと見せかけて
それしかないと思わせる
The two of us aren't very different, are we?
僕らは そう変わりないだろう？
Let me guess. You never
wanted to be a sorcerer, did you?
もしかして 君…
本当は魔術師になんか
なりたくなかったんじゃ
ないのかい？
Did someone force you?
誰かに強制でも…
Don't you dare choose my path for me.
私の道を勝手に決めるな
That girl is mine.
（エリアス）
あの子は僕のものだよ
That's what Chise wants.
チセは
そう望んでくれてる
It'll be interesting to see how long that lasts.
いつまで続くか 見ものだな
Living creatures change, whether they desire it or not.
生物は変わる
望もうが望むまいが…
A-Awkward, huh?
（アリス）き… 気まずいっすね
Yeah.
That pile of bones doesn't get it, though.
でも あの骨 分かっちゃいねっすよ
There's a ton of people who
can only tread their own path,
線路を走るみたいに
しむけられてもさ
even when they're shown rails to follow.
結局 自分の道しか走れないヤツは
ごまんといるんだ
君は自分の道を走ってる？
Do you tread your own path?
The paths form where I choose to tread.
自分が選んで走った所に
道が出来るんですよ
It's nice to be young.
（アドルフ）若いって いいねえ
We hereby begin the six o'clock auction.
（競売人）
それでは
18時からの競りを開始いたします
The northern land of dragons is sealed off.
今は閉ざされた北のドラゴンの国
そこで育ちました
純粋なる翼竜種の雛でございます！
It was there that this
purebred, winged dragon was raised!
Starting at 800,000.
（競売人）それでは 80万から！
810,000.
（客Ａ）81！
（客Ｂ）82！
820,000.
850,000.
（客Ｃ）85！
900,000.
（客Ｄ）90… 90！
900,000!
920,000.
（客Ｃ）92！
One million!
（客Ｄ）100！
The college can manage up to 1.5 million.
（アドルフ）
150までは
ギリギリ カレッジで出せます
If we go over...
超えたら そのときは…
（チセ）分かってます
I know.
（アドルフ）出品者は？
Who's the exhibitor?
あれです
Him.
1,220,000!
（客）122！
A proxy.
（アドルフ）雇われか…
1,250,000!
Or a proxy for a proxy.
（トーリー）雇われの雇われかも
1,250,000.
（競売人）125！ 125！
That person's looking at me.
（チセ）
あの人… こっちを見てる
1,500,000.
（競売人）150！
（チセ）ハッ…
1,500,000!
（競売人）150です！
（セス）どこまで いきますか？
How high shall we go?
As high as you know my balance goes.
あなたの知っている残高まで
All right.
了解しました
1,600,000!
（競売人）160！
They're gone.
（チセ）いない？
（競売人）170！
1,700,000.
Anyone else?
（競売人）
ほかに どなたか
いらっしゃいませんか？
Do we have anyone else?
Hello, young lady.
（マリエル）こんにちは お嬢さん
Is something wrong?
（エリアス）どうかした？
いえ…
No.
No one else can hear me.
（マリエル）
あなた以外に 聞こえてはいないわ
Don't worry.
大丈夫よ
Who are you?
（チセ）
あなたは誰ですか？
A woman that you could make use of.
（マリエル）
あなたにとって 都合のいい女
Is that good enough?
で… いいかしら
Use you?
（チセ）
都合？
1,800,000.
（競売人）180！
180！
1,850,000.
（客）185！
（競売人）185！
1,850,000.
（客）191！
1,910,000.
（競売人）191！
1,930,000.
（客）193！
（競売人）193！
1,930,000.
1,970,000.
（客）197！
Please do it if we're at our limit.
（チセ）
こちらの底が見えたら
よろしくお願いします
Otherwise, don't.
そうでなければ なしで
It's too bad this is only a verbal agreement.
（マリエル）耳約束なのが残念ね
Please don't go home with any regrets.
皆様 後悔なさいませんように
いかがですか？
Well?
2,600,000.
260！
2,900,000.
（競売人）290！
This looks promising.
いけそうですね
に… 290！
2,900,000.
We're at 2,900,000.
290です！
Anyone for more than 2,900,000?
それ以上 上の方は
いらっしゃいませんか？
Damn it, that was reinforced with a specialized spell.
（バイヤーＡ）
おい 専用の強化呪縛式だぞ
なんで破れる？
How did it get out?!
I don't know.
（バイヤーＢ）
分かりません！
こんなことは 初めてで…
We've never had this happen!
It's not...
どう見ても…
...in its right mind.
（レンフレッド）正気じゃないな
Chise!
（エリアス）チセ
He wants to go home.
帰りたがってる
He's scared.
怖がってるし…
He's so miserable.
すごく… 嫌がってる
You can hear the dragon's voice?!
ドラゴンの声が聞こえるのか？
ハアッ ハアッ…
It's all right.
（エリアス）
大丈夫 それは君の感情じゃない
Those aren't your emotions.
You don't need to let them take you.
引っ張られなくていい
マズ…
Shit!
The moon witnessed our incomplete cycles.
tsuki wa miteita kaketeru bokura
We called to one another,
tagai wo yobiai nagara
Walking distant paths as we took the long way around.
toomawari de tooi michi wo aruita
Red and black attract one another...
hikiyoseau aka to kuro ga
Shadow and light chase after one another...
oikakeau yami to hikari ga
They're made of two related things
futatsu no tsuranaru mono de tsukurareteru yo
...everything in this world is.
konoyo no subete wa
Because you're here, I'm here.
anata ga iru kara watashi wa iru
Even apart, we're side by side.
hanaretemo soba ni iru
soba ni iru
We're side by side.
Everyone is continually searching
daremo ga jibun no mou hitotsu no
For one precious thing
kataware to iu taisetsu na mono
That they can call their other half.
sagashi tsudzuketeru yo
The dragon's sorrowful howls
echo through the skies of London.
（チセ）
ドラゴンの悲しき咆哮(ほうこう)が
ロンドンの空に響く
The girl makes a decision to save
the dragon, but it was far too brutal.
ドラゴンを救うため
少女が下した結論は
あまりにも過酷なものだった
It's okay.
（チセ）大丈夫　一緒に帰ろう
Let's go home together.